# Abe Schur



flex4lease@gmail.com



773-999-6902



linkedin.com/in/abe-schur-40b55119a

## **Summary**

Skilled programmer software developer in Javascript and React.js obsessed with fixing bugs and writing sleek and optimized code. I will not rest until all your bugs have been squashed, your applications are running smoothly and efficiently, and your codebase is fully optimized. I have built large custom fullstack application and REST API's. I probably have more experience than your average bootcamp graduate or college undergraduate, so give me a chance to show you what I can do for your company!

Checkout my full online resume for in depth project details and links: https://elegant-lichterman-1fc4e5.netlify.app/

Some of my recent projects and skill sets:

- •Software design and full automation of real estate buisness logic in a Javascript React.js and firebase progressive web app, with IVR voice system scheduling, coupon generation, web push, twilio SMS, sendgrid, and PayPal integration
- A free listing platform for real estate for sale and for lease Built in PHP MYSQL, any user can sign up and list spaces
- Functional Programming, OOP, Foreign Languages, Software Development and Optimization

## **Experience**



#### **Javascript Developer**

#### **GREYSTONE ASSOCIATES LIMITED**

Jan 2016 - Present (5 years 4 months +)

Software Design, fully automate all real estate business logic with Full Stack React.js Express Application

- Build a multi-listing real estate application in PHP MySQL
- Responsible for all digital marketing and design

#### Security Manager

Jan 2015 - Jan 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Provided security for schools, churches, synagogues and at events

- Coordinated with local law enforcement on security procedures
- Drafted security procedures and reports
- Scheduled security shifts and fill gaps in security schedule



#### **Team Lead**

Maritime Security

Jan 2012 - Jan 2014 (2 years 1 month)

Responsible for training and equipment of Maritime Security Team

• Trained foreign security and military personnel in anti-piracy procedures

## ■ Team Lead

#### **BOWLINE DEFENCE LIMITED**

Maintained crew reaction procedures to piracy attacks through drills and set standards

- Maintained proficiency of Ship Layout and clearing procedures, Marsat communications systems
- Briefed and advised the captain of the vessel on security measures
- Worked with United Nations Maritime Task Operations as necessary
- Coordinated the security response before and during a piracy attack

## Guard

Jan 2011 - Jan 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Conducted interview and visitation procedures in multiple languages to citizenship applicants

• Escort and security for government employees

### **Education**



B.A, Arabic and Persian Language and Linguistics

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

(A) API's and Microservices - freeCodeCamp

https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/kravmaguy/apis-and-microservices

(A) Javascript data structures and algorithms - freeCodeCamp

https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/kravmaguy/javascript-algorithms-and-d

#### Skills

api • application development • Foreign Languages • React.js • PHP • Software Development • Express.js • WordPress • Functional Programming • Twilio